oh my goodness New Zealand is known as
one of the world's most scenic countries
and what better way to see it than by
train in fact Sitting In First Class
with a glass of sparkling wine kind of
train is there any better way to travel
we're about to ride two trains and a
ferry over 2 days to take us from the
south island to the top of the North
Island gosh that's gorgeous welcome to
Downey live and we're starting this
morning on the south island in Christ
Church so welcome aboard kiwi rail one
of the great journeys of New Zealand all
right morning morning we all set we're
all set perfect fantastic 14 just the
table on the right hand side and one of
us thank you perfect and I am riding
today with my old friend Seb do you want
the window seat or the aisle seat you
get the window it's too nice look at
this wow look at the detailing on the
ceiling this is our menu for the trip
and you can see where some of the local
ingredients have come from so including
the butter the cheese the lamb the
mushrooms
all from the island here here we go 2
minutes early that never happens that
doesn't happen in
Canada our journey starts by rolling
past parking lots and warehouses but
pretty quickly we get up to speed and
are offered a hot towel to freshen up
that's
okay thank you very
much this is a warm welcome isn't it it
is very warm and moist oh my one thing I
want you to notice listen how quiet it
is that's pretty good and it's not long
before I see why this is called one of
the world's most scenic train rides
beautiful but we're going to have to
stop looking out the window for a minute
because breakfast is served breakfast
starts with a spinach feta loaf sounds
delicious yeah looks delicious that's
really nice and this butter we know
where it came from thanks to the map
where was again where was it this is a
full service train experience and
there's nothing I like more than eating
on board a train at full speed thank you
so much you're welcome oh beautiful
cheers Mike
cheers a good coffee all right now we're
off to a good start oh yeah now the
views out the window at this point are
exactly what you'd expect in New Zealand
an abundance of sheep and lamb as well
as a few Vineyards which I'm looking
forward to trying a little later on but
as comfortable as it is to sit here and
enjoy it all Seb has a better idea all
right should we check out the deck oh
yeah oh yeah there's a deck at the back
of the train is an outdoor deck space
which is great for three reasons one it
gives you room to walk around and
stretch your legs on board two you can
get some fresh air throughout the day
and three it's better for photos as you
don't get any glare from Windows and you
can see the whole train ahead of you as
we go around corners
and look at this
backdrop we have only been on the train
for an hour or so so far and I'm told
it's only going to get better now it's
not all just green fields and Rolling
Hills there are bridges
too
holy okay New Zealand's turning up for
us right now now Seb and I have come
back to our seats because it's it's time
for second breakfast more food waiting
for my coffee to eat this in combination
dip
yeah these Green Hills are so peaceful
like this is a very calming train ride
wait I just saw a hobbit you saw a
hobbit now is a good time for a bathroom
tour oh that's cool I thought it would
slide in rotates look at that okay right
away for accessibility this is huge this
is
awesome cool now the trick with these
you have to remember to lock the door
otherwise someone can open it from
outside good this is absolutely huge
it's not that fancy but it
works but I will give them extra credit
cuz I this is the coolest bathroom door
I've ever
seen look at that
oh the scenery is changing the scenery
is
changing ladies and gentlemen we are
seeing for the first time the ocean for
the next few hours we'll be running