oh my goodness New Zealand is known as
one of the world's most scenic countries
and what better way to see it than by
train in fact Sitting In First Class
with a glass of sparkling wine kind of
train is there any better way to travel
we're about to ride two trains and a
ferry over 2 days to take us from the
south island to the top of the North
Island gosh that's gorgeous welcome to
Downey live and we're starting this
morning on the south island in Christ
Church so welcome aboard kiwi rail one
of the great journeys of New Zealand all
right morning morning we all set we're
all set perfect fantastic 14 just the
table on the right hand side and one of
us thank you perfect and I am riding
today with my old friend Seb do you want
the window seat or the aisle seat you
get the window it's too nice look at
this wow look at the detailing on the
ceiling this is our menu for the trip
and you can see where some of the local
ingredients have come from so including
the butter the cheese the lamb the
mushrooms
all from the island here here we go 2
minutes early that never happens that
doesn't happen in
Canada our journey starts by rolling
past parking lots and warehouses but
pretty quickly we get up to speed and
are offered a hot towel to freshen up
that's
okay thank you very
much this is a warm welcome isn't it it
is very warm and moist oh my one thing I
want you to notice listen how quiet it
is that's pretty good and it's not long
before I see why this is called one of
the world's most scenic train rides
beautiful but we're going to have to
stop looking out the window for a minute
because breakfast is served breakfast
starts with a spinach feta loaf sounds
delicious yeah looks delicious that's
really nice and this butter we know
where it came from thanks to the map
where was again where was it this is a
full service train experience and
there's nothing I like more than eating
on board a train at full speed thank you
so much you're welcome oh beautiful
cheers Mike
cheers a good coffee all right now we're
off to a good start oh yeah now the
views out the window at this point are
exactly what you'd expect in New Zealand
an abundance of sheep and lamb as well
as a few Vineyards which I'm looking
forward to trying a little later on but
as comfortable as it is to sit here and
enjoy it all Seb has a better idea all
right should we check out the deck oh
yeah oh yeah there's a deck at the back
of the train is an outdoor deck space
which is great for three reasons one it
gives you room to walk around and
stretch your legs on board two you can
get some fresh air throughout the day
and three it's better for photos as you
don't get any glare from Windows and you
can see the whole train ahead of you as
we go around corners
and look at this
backdrop we have only been on the train
for an hour or so so far and I'm told
it's only going to get better now it's
not all just green fields and Rolling
Hills there are bridges
too
holy okay New Zealand's turning up for
us right now now Seb and I have come
back to our seats because it's it's time
for second breakfast more food waiting
for my coffee to eat this in combination
dip
yeah these Green Hills are so peaceful
like this is a very calming train ride
wait I just saw a hobbit you saw a
hobbit now is a good time for a bathroom
tour oh that's cool I thought it would
slide in rotates look at that okay right
away for accessibility this is huge this
is
awesome cool now the trick with these
you have to remember to lock the door
otherwise someone can open it from
outside good this is absolutely huge
it's not that fancy but it
works but I will give them extra credit
cuz I this is the coolest bathroom door
I've ever
seen look at that
oh the scenery is changing the scenery
is
changing ladies and gentlemen we are
seeing for the first time the ocean for
the next few hours we'll be running
along the east coast with ocean views on
the right hand side while there's still
valleys and mountains on our
left but that's not all there are
tunnels too look at this view look at
this view that's what we came to
see that's what we
oh look at this long tunnel oh there we
go wow it's like the California
coastline this really is one of those
train rides where you don't know where
to look do you watch the train snake
ahead of you take in the ocean or peek
ahead of the snow capped
mountains luckily this train has it all
so you don't really need to decide oh
it's amazing better than way better than
I thought what a
you wow now I thought second breakfast
was a lot but here we are with third
breakfast oh my gosh smoked salmon
poached egg hollay sauce on roasted
potatoes I don't know where to start
with this it's quite a few courses on
today's ride but they're all pretty well
spaced apart and I've said this before
but there really is no better type of
restaurant than one that moves with a
view like this and what a view what a
restaurant View
now whenever we're able to get out and
stretch our legs for a second I always
like to take advantage of it we've
arrived at a train station we can step
off for a minute but we don't want to go
too far what a
view we can come out see the front of
the train which is pretty amazing you
can see this the ocean right there and
the mountains in the background but I
get so anxious that the Train's going to
leave without us so uh I'm just going to
dash back to the
door okay okay
okay as beautiful as this place is I do
not want to be left behind here here we
go where's Seb where's Seb SE Seb oh
they almost left me
there no one waves any you mate everyone
Wes there we go thank
you back to the ocean
news this water looks so turquoise and
tropical it's a incredible I would I
wouldn't have guessed we're in New
Zealand oh my goodness I really don't
know which side to look at we got
mountains on one side and ocean on the
other where the
cows I mean I don't know where else in
the world you can see all of that in one
shot
I mean it's got everything it's even got
highways we spending more time outside
than on extra seats yeah
yeah that is true we're not spending
much time in our seats at all you pay
for your seats but really all you need
is this outdoor car because this is a
Scenic rail experience we booked it to
see the scenery of New Zealand and it
has absolutely delivered so
far just ignore the crazy wind hair I
mean I'm really enjoying it out there
that's the whole point of this so this
is Scenic class and it is very Scenic
they still have the huge Windows they
have a couple of
4x4 tables uh and then the rest of it is
sort of 2 by two seating while Scenic
plus is what we've Chosen and that comes
with higher end food white tablecloth
service and all of
that wow just doesn't stop I thought we
left the co behind but now it's back
this is really incredible I've seen some
fantastic train trips in my life and
this
is this is up there with one of the best
I agree I haven't done as much as you
but and the experience only continues to
get better oh thank you Sasha you're
welcome we are celebrating a 60th
wedding anniversary
congratulations Cheers
Cheers Cheers guys cheers with our new
train friend
yeah is there any better way to travel
than sparkling wine on a train by the
coast I don't think so I don't think so
starting at 9:00 yes
starting and we won't tell you what time
this is right now but let's just say we
haven't had lunch yet now I have to say
these lovely ladies to our left are from
New Zealand and they're friends they
decided to take a train trip together
and seeing this really gives we hope
that maybe seven I still in the future
will be riding trains together at their
age I hope our lunch doesn't come out
too
salty oh my go
oh oh wow ni wild rice and chicken wild
rice and chicken that's thank you so
lovely okay now this is our last meal on
board this
train so we have wild rice with
chicken and New Zealand s Blan from the
region here bon
bon the views never stop they never stop
oh here's a winery could it be could it
be probably not but same region as we
finish our lunch and even a dessert
there's more dessert there's more view
more water Seb do you know why this
dessert reminds me of Canada nope it's
moose
I don't know if I'm making Everyone
likes your puns yeah I don't know if I'm
making friends or losing friends out
here the train is still pulling us along
getting us even closer to the town of
pikon which has just comeing to view now
along with the fery so we're coming into
the town of pikon now which is where
we're going to get off the train and
onto our Ferry for the afternoon I'm
excited for the ferry yeah this is it
this is us us arriving at the
platform cool it's a modern day
turntable
wow I don't know if I've ever seen a
real one like a functional one in real
life before that's so cool thank you bye
bye cute all right now we have to go
find our fairy to go check in let's do
it see you Sasha thanks guys it's nice
to meet you nice to meet you man nice to
meet you enjoy your travels guys you I
think we're looking for a very large
boat now this should be a very easy
connection come out of the train station
we're looking for the inter Islander and
it's right there I see it Mike you sees
it I see it honestly it's it's literally
next door it couldn't be easier yeah 5
minute walk
less oh that was easy wow this looks
like an airport and I like to see that
come on man that is good news little
excitement yeah I know heavy storm thank
you thank so much the timing of the
ferry is set to depart pretty much just
after we arrived by train so we pretty
much just walked straight onto the
ferry oh we're on
board this is a big Ferry the ferry
itself is huge holy cow there's 10
levels where do you want to start
starting to feel like a cruise ship it
does the interior is very spacious with
plenty of indoor seating areas okay this
is
nice nice cafeteria but we just ate on
the train so do you want to sit outside
or inside let's check out how warm it is
outside all right let's go outside
oh it's a heavy Dart it is a perfect day
to be outside but it's not long before
we're pulling out of
pikon and that is it we're off so we're
on the ferry for the next 4 hours
and couldn't be happier yeah heading to
the North Island this is going to be
great gosh it is so pretty here the
water and Landscape here almost looks
tropical at times but it's not quite as
warm as tropical the water look color
looks so nice I want to jump in I don't
really have a lot to say about the ferry
it's a very standard Ferry but we're
here for this and this is
delivering the southern section of this
fery ride has us Meandering along the
toor ranui sound and alongside a few
Islands but eventually we come out to
the open Waters of cook straight this
only happens twice a day passing our
sister ship so there's uh one fairy that
goes out in the morning and obviously
one that goes back in the morning and
then we're on the afternoon one can you
see anyone waving
Seb they waving back are they waving
back well I like to think the people
inside saw me
waving that's enough for me they all
waving Mike yeah yeah I think so yeah
yeah yeah that is the end of the south
island and that is the tip of the North
Island we can already see how much more
populated the north island is in fact
76% of New Zealand residents live on the
North Island and we are pulling in to
the capital of New Zealand the beautiful
city of Wellington there is Wellington
welcome let's head in get ready to
offload see right there
wow all right Wellington we've made it
to Wellington now we have to find our
hotel now the terminal on this side is
being upgraded so there's a temporary
luggage pickup area I'm not sure what
kind of temporary building this is but
an interesting tent Style
it's like an airport luggage area in the
middle of a parking lot just with some
plastic up to keep it
dry it's not beautiful but it all seems
to work and we have our luggage now we
have to get to town let's go find our
hotel luckily they have a solution for
us there is a free shuttle that takes us
to the train station which we're not
catching the train today we are going to
our hotel our train is tomorrow morning
but we're staying not too far away today
was a pretty full day with a train a
ferry and a bus thank you let's check
the map now now we're going to walk to
the hotel yeah do we sharing a room I
don't know I've never seen that's 601
this is 602 and
603 and we're
603 oh okay oh it's nice
oh
perfect separate beds but very close
just the way we like
them but it does come with a view of the
train
tracks okay we only have a few hours
this evening in Wellington so the one
thing we have to do the cable car
obviously as it is one of the top
visitor attractions in
town it's surprisingly quiet at the
moment but this finic carries about a
million passengers a year and I can see
why it's like really cute do you want
the do you want the front or the bottom
top or the bottom bottom got it found my
seat
perfect here we go ladies and gentlemen
now the cable car only goes about 18 km
an hour or so we're going to speed it up
in editing here but it does have some
nice murals on the way up and I really
like this tunnel with neon lights that
is cool has disco lights that is cool
I told I told you cable cars are cool
yeah and of course like any finic the
track splits in the middle uhoh uhoh to
let the cable cars pass well we only had
an hour or so to do something before it
closed but worth it yeah Wellington
Cable Car approved and after 2,000 ft we
have arrived at the top of the line it's
like a very slow Scenic roller
coaster well we made it up here just
about it sun set but the sun set's on
the other side but still what a view
yeah and now I can see why it is one of
the most popular attractions here in
Wellington it's very quiet and peaceful
yeah and it reminds me a little bit of
Canada yeah the buildings are a little
different though like it's like a mix of
Canada and San Francisco yeah now the
best part of these types of trips is the
free time and really not knowing where
you'll end up tonight's choice of
restaurant happens to be over a hundred
years old and has live jazz tonight
[Music]
I'd say exploring Wellington was a
success but we have to get to bed
because we have an early morning train
to
catch there it is there it is literally
we got to go oh damn we got to go let's
go let's go oh my my
suitcase go
go go go go
[Music]
watch out for the Post what
please oh sorry you're early guys oh my
sorry sorry let's
go fair is fair you can have the window
today really yeah okay looks like we're
on a romantic train journey it does a a
bromantic journey oh my goodness I'm
just taking a look at the menu now and I
am not used to eating this much we get a
baked treat a cold breakfast then a hot
breakfast then lunch a little later on
followed by a sweet treat then an
afternoon platter cuz why not then
straight into dinner plus dessert I
don't know when we're going to have time
to be on the back deck when we're going
to be sitting and eating all day what
are you talking about you ate that much
yesterday it feels maybe I'm just still
full maybe the hobbits were right maybe
in New Zealand there is second breakfast
with the cold and hot breakfast I won't
say no to
that as long as they're different
temperatures and we're off all right
headed north to a
in 10 hours from now that's right today
is going to be a full day on board as we
will be crossing the entire North Island
and service starts again with a warm tow
o wow thank you so much say it was
intimate didn't it
did dab my sweat
away need so we're on our way out of
Wellington past the ferry we rode in on
we're moving now and are very quickly
served our first bit of breakfast Chia
Chia
honey we are about to cross five
viaducts and here's the
first now the spectacular part of
today's journey is the fact that we'll
have a little bit more height than we
did
yesterday
wow and with views like these the
outdoor car at the back is much busier
today
o r wow
rub that's cool along with viu we also
get to cut through some hillsides with
longer tunnels today
too oh my gosh it's lunchtime
already wow thank you we're having
quinoa salad with
with
lamb I even spotted some Wildlife out
here that's not sheap too
wow some more surprising than
others now I think it's clear today's
landscape is very different from
yesterdays and it's hard to pick which
one is better but this different Flora
is a sign we've entered the tongariro
National Park which holds perhaps the
most impressive feature of of this trip
oh wow we got a volcano we're cruising
along a volcanic Plateau which is why it
feels suddenly so different to what we
had been seeing but it's not long before
we move from a natural wonder to an
engineering wonder the spiral tunnels
you see those tracks below that's where
we're going to come out so they call us
an engineering Marvel we're about to go
around the top of the mountain into a
tunnel come un tunnel underneath where
we are right now
and then do a big horseshoe curve and
that is to drop 139 M now I will admit
for most of us you can't actually see
much but occasionally you can spot the
tracks on this spiral
segment we're going to go through two
tunnels a short one now we're going into
the long one with a long
curve W that's cool now we're going
around down and then under right yeah
yeah we're going to come out of the
tunnel underneath where we
started pretty that's a long my tunnel I
guess yeah there there
go and we were up
there this is something you really could
miss if you weren't looking for it but
on a 10-hour train ride you take all the
excitement you can get hold on
that was the tightest corner of our
entire trip yes the little things you
got to you got to enjoy the little
moments on a long train R like this take
what you get yeah we've got all day yeah
all right let's go get that cheese
platter oh
yeah oh wow thank you say cheese cheese
got to say this cheese plate looks
really gooda but uh I've already had it
before so
too cheesy a little
bit little
bit you're spending a lot of time
looking out the windows it's so look at
the landscape now most of the afternoon
is spent in these seats eating more yeah
cheers man cheers hey good trip good
trip thanks so so far good trip yeah
very good trip thanks for coming now I
can say the view has stayed pretty
consistently amazing I mean it has
changed throughout the 2-day journey
which has kept it interesting all the
the way through but I think it's clear
why this is called one of the great
Railway Journeys in New Zealand but
eventually you will notice signs that
we're approaching
civilization which can only mean one
thing I think this is it yeah 10 minutes
Areo and we're in ockland We Made It 2
days from Christ Church to Picton a
fairy to Wellington and the train all
the way to Auckland glad we made it
it's been a long day yes it is it's just
been a long day of food but it's been
pretty wonderful you still
rolling I just want to
say thanks for coming along a know where
I'm going next but I know I want you get
with that's that's my line oh a long two
days but a beautiful two days really was
thank you guys bye so nice meet you
K but if if you think arriving in
Auckland is the endend of this
experience I have good news for you Seb
and I are going to drive golf carts on
train tracks and that video is already
up to watch right now on nebula an
independent Creator own streaming
platform I mean this rail cart
experience has us riding through 20
tunnels across 90 Bridges and along 100
miles of track and you can watch it
right now on nebula in fact nebula is
great because it doesn't have any ads or
sponsorships and you're not only getting
my videos over there but nebula has
hundreds of creators like real
engineering a channel on impressive
engineering or you can watch a fun
travel show called jet lag the game
where three friends use the globe as
their board game but nebula also has
shows you can only watch over there like
the getaway where a bunch of contestants
are all told they are the snitch and
hilarity ensues so if you want to watch
Seb and I drive a golf cart on a real
Railway right now now use my link to
nebula to get 40% off an annual
subscription and help support creators
so visit
[Music]